The Helpful Apprentice
There was once a small restaurant.
People said that the best chef in the world worked there.
But the chef was a horrible person to work for.
He was impolite and scolded his workers all the time.
The chef had a young apprentice.
The apprentice's first priority was to make the best food in the world.
He was happy to have a good teacher, but he didn't like the chef.
The boy was a diligent worker,
but the chef scolded him more than anyone else.
Then one day, the chef got great news.
The emperor wanted to have dinner there that night.
He was very excited.
He was working very fast, and he made a mistake.
He cut his hand with a knife, and it started to bleed.
The apprentice gave him a bandage, but the chef still couldn't cook.
The chef started to panic.
The apprentice tried to assure him.
"Everything will be OK," he said.
But the chef was still afraid.
Then they started to work together.
They began to bond.
The chef told the apprentice what to do, and the boy cooked a great meal.
As soon as they finished, the emperor arrived.
He wore a beautiful robe made of soft fibers.
He also had a massive crown.
Everyone in the restaurant kneeled when the emperor came in.
The chef and the boy brought out his food.
The emperor was used to luxuries.
Would he like the food?
The emperor loved the food.
After his departure, the chef was very proud and very thankful to his new friend, the apprentice.