July 28, 2017
Dear Diary, I am beyond excited!
My cousin Ella is coming all the way from England for a visit.
We haven't seen each other for many years.
Ella's plane will land soon,
and I want to be a gracious host and get everything ready to welcome my special guest from abroad.
The warm temperature in July is just right.
Earlier today, I opened the window to let in fresh air and looked outside.
The afternoon sky was a brilliant blue,
the grass was a fresh emerald green,
and the pink roses were in full bloom.
It was a stunning display of natural beauty.
Ella is coming at the perfect time!
I still have to finish cleaning up and then vacuum the carpet.
I have already stocked the refrigerator with Ella's favorite foods.
Last night, I set out clean towels and arranged the guest bedroom for Ella.
I will set out toiletries and other things soon.
I want to go over the activity list for Ella's visit one last time.
I made sure to keep a copy of the list on my desk and also on my computer.
I meticulously planned the details for each day so that they are productive and packed with fun-filled activities,
I know that Ella loves history,
so we will visit the museum on Monday,
where there is a special show about architecture in modern cities.
We will go to the art gallery on Tuesday and see the latest works of contemporary art.
I also want to take Ella to the upper part of town because that is where the best shopping and sales are.
Then, we'll watch Hamlet, a Shakespearean play being performed at the local drama theater.
I also want to take Ella on a canoe ride and enjoy the many lakes around the city.
We can pack a picnic basket, have lunch at the lake, and enjoy the beautiful weather outside.
I am really excited about it because I've never been on a canoe ride!
There are so many sightseeing opportunities and so much to show Ella,
but I also want to spend time at home with Ella so we can both relax and catch up.
I'd better run because it's almost time to pick up Ella at the airport.
I can't wait to see Ella!
love, Gemma