The Boy and His Sled
Mike was the smallest child in school.
Another boy, Joe, always teased Mike.
Joe had a large scar on his face from fighting other children.
One day, Joe offended Mike when he made fun of Mike's valentine, Jane.
This was disgraceful, but Mike didn't know how to make Joe stop.
That day, Mike walked home down an alley.
He found a bunch of wood boards next to a pine tree.
He thought to himself,
"I could build a decent sled from these.
If I let Joe use it,
he will be nicer to me and Jane."
He took the wood home.
Mike got an ax and cut the wood.
He used nails to make sure that the pieces were not loose.
As he worked, he bumped his elbow on the boards.
The painful sensation made him want to cry.
It was a hard chore, but he persisted.
He worked overnight.
By morning, the sled was finished.
Mike called Joe on the telephone.
He said, "Hi, Joe. Come over to my house right away."
Joe didn't know why Mike wanted him to come over.
When Joe arrived, Mike told him,
"Joe, it irritated me the other day when you said mean things about Jane.
You weren't kidding when you said those mean things.
But I'm not like you.
I just built this sled, and I'll let you ride it with me if you are nice."
They became friends, and Joe was grateful that Mike was so nice to him.
He learned that it is more fun to be nice than to be mean.