Lazy Hans
Hans was lazy.
He seldom helped his mother with anything.
He didn't cook, and he never mowed the lawn.
He didn't even shave!
He spent the daytime gambling with his mother's money.
One day, his mother realized that her money was gone from her purse.
"You're banned from my house!" she shouted.
"Don't come back until you've learned your lesson!"
Hans went to live in the forest like an outlaw.
But it was cold, and Hans couldn't find any food.
He went to a cottage to ask for a meal.
A wizard answered the door.
"Can I stay here, please?" Hans asked.
"You can stay if you work," the man replied.
Hans liked the prospect of food and warmth, so he agreed.
The man pointed to a field.
"Take this rod and plant it over there.
I am a wizard, and this magic rod will bring us food."
The field was far away.
Hans knew it would be exhausting to walk there.
So he just threw the rod behind the cottage and sat by the river.
When daylight faded, he returned to the cottage and went to sleep.
The next morning, the old man looked very fierce.
"You didn't take the rod to the field!" he shouted.
"No," confessed Hans, "it was too far!"
"Because of you, we have nothing to eat!" replied the man.
Hans was terrified that the man would punish him.
So he ran home.
"Mama!" he cried, "I'm desperate to come back!"
His mother was cautious.
"Do you promise to work?" she asked.
"Yes!" said Hans, "I'll never be lazy again!"