Sheriff Dan
Dan was the evil sheriff of Oceantown.
Dan was as cruel as the devil.
He worshiped money.
Dan was a millionaire, but he paid his police officers almost nothing.
The police were very bitter, but Dan didn't care.
He only cared about his money.
Every person who inhabited Oceantown disliked him.
Dan enforced cruel laws.
Once, Dan even put his own brother in jail for throwing a coin into a fountain!
Sometimes, he pointed his gun into the air and pulled the trigger.
He didn't want the bullets to hit anyone.
He just wanted to scare people with the loud sound.
Finally, the people of Oceantown decided that they had to get rid of Sheriff Dan,
and tried to find some way to do this.
Their wish to get rid of Dan helped to unify the town.
They marched to Dan's house.
He was startled by the sight when he ran to the door.
When he opened the door, the crowd jumped on him.
They used a rope to tie him to a chair.
Dan yelled, "Get your hands off me!
I'll put you all in jail for the rest of your lives!"
The crowd didn't listen.
They carried Dan to the harbor and put him aboard a vessel.
Dan was so scared that he began to sweat.
He begged, "If you let me go, I will give you all my money!"
The crowd said, "Sheriff, we don't care about your money.
We know you will never change.
We're sending you on a voyage to the middle of the ocean."
The boat drifted out of the port, and Dan was never seen again.
The people chose a new sheriff, who was kind and fair.