The Magic Pear Tree
It was a cool morning, and the grass was covered in mist.
The market was full of people.
A mean farmer named Jack yelled, "Pears for sale!"
He sat on a bench, plotting how he could trick people.
Then, an orphan came to his cart.
"Can you spare a pear?" she asked.
Jack felt rage.
He replied, "You don't have any money!"
"Please, I haven't had supper in days."
"No!" shouted the farmer.
The orphan sighed.
However, a pregnant lady heard the dispute and came over to Jack.
"Just give her a pear," she said.
Jack had no shame and said no.
Finally, a man bought a pear for the girl.
The girl quickly ate it, but she saved the seed.
She wanted to get revenge.
She told Jack, "I know a way to get hundreds of pears in one day.
I'll show you how."
He watched the girl dig a hole.
She dropped the seed into the ground.
Then she spread the dirt over it.
"Watch closely," she said.
"In a few minutes, a stem will grow.
It'll turn into a tree that's full of pears!"
Jack stared at the dirt, but nothing happened.
The only objects there were a few daisies.
He looked for the girl, but she had snuck away.
Then, he looked at his cart in horror.
It was empty!
He suddenly realized that the orphan had tricked him.
While Jack was waiting for the tree to grow, the people had taken the pears from his cart.
They all laughed while they were eating the tender fruit.
The farmer felt ashamed.
The incident taught him to be kinder.