The Senator and the Worm
A rich senator lived in a big house.
He had more money than anyone in his district.
One day, he was sitting on a chair listening to a radio broadcast.
As he listened to the news bulletin,
a worm crawled from underneath the chair and onto his head.
His cook was in the kitchen stirring some spaghetti sauce.
Suddenly, a cry from the senator alerted him.
He ran to the rear of the house where the senator was sitting.
The cook looked and saw the worm.
He tried to console the senator.
"I'll take it off right away," he said.
"No!" shouted the senator. "I want you to kill it."
"But it's only a worm," the cook said.
"Why should we execute it? It hasn't committed a crime."
The senator could not endure the worm on his head. "Hurry!" he shouted.
The cook looked through several drawers but found nothing.
Then he ran to the closet and took out a pipe.
He returned to the senator and lifted the pipe over his head.
He knew he couldn't just tap the worm.
He was going to hit it hard.
He grasped the pipe tightly.
"What are you waiting for?" said the senator. "Kill it!"
The cook swung the pipe at the senator's head.
"Oh, no," the worm said.
"He's going to chop me in half."
It jumped off the senator's head.
There was a tremendous noise.
"Owww!" cried the senator.
A bump rose upon his skull.
Meanwhile, the worm crawled outside.
"That was close," said the worm,
"Instead of being nice, he wanted to hurt me.
Now, that man has a big bump on his head."