Why Monkey Has No Home
For five years, there was a famine.
The farmers asked people to bless them, and finally they had a good harvest.
Since there was now plenty of food, the pharaoh decided to have a party.
The party was a happy affair.
For five days, they had a huge feast.
Monkey was very happy.
Because of the famine, he was very slim.
He wanted to eat a lot of food.
When he arrived at the feast hundreds of long tables were filled with food.
There were nuts, bowls of cereal, and ripe fruit.
He could also smell hot roasted meat cooking on the stove.
The assembly of animals was merry.
However, during the meal, Monkey thought of a scheme to exploit the pharaoh's kindness.
He decided to steal some of the food and then eat it at home.
All the animals were cheerful.
They didn't notice that Monkey was hiding food.
After the feast, Monkey took the food to his house and ate it.
He repeated this routine every day for four days.
But on the fifth day, the pharaoh had a surprise.
He was going to give all the animals a home.
Monkey was very excited.
But when he arrived at the pharaoh's home, he could not get through the door.
The diameter of his waist was wider than the door, He was too fat!
Monkey asked the pharaoh to forgive him for his theft.
But the pharaoh said no.
"Pardon?" asked the monkey.
He didn't understand why the pharaoh was being unkind.
"Everybody else will have a home now, but not you.
Now you know that greed gets you nothing," explained the pharaoh.