Matthew Learns a Lesson
Matthew was an adolescent and a sensible boy.
He always kept his room tidy and had a natural literary aptitude.
He hoped to one day have a career in journalism.
He spent much of his time reading and liked his privacy.
But his quiet personality hindered his ability to make friends.
One day, Matthew went to the pharmacy to pick up some pills for his grandmother.
He saw some boys leaning against a tree outside.
One of the boys complimented Matthew: "I like your jacket."
Another boy asked, "Do you want to go to Nate's Restaurant?" "Sure!" Matthew said.
The boys walked to the restaurant.
They were going to have slices of pizza.
They ordered their food and drank soda with straws.
They ate until their bellies swelled up.
Matthew was having so much fun.
One of the boys said, "Let's leave without paying."
Matthew didn't want to.
But he presumed his new friends wouldn't like him if he didn't.
Suddenly, the waiter yelled,
"Stop!" The two other boys ran, leaving Matthew there alone.
Soon, the police arrived.
"Leaving without paying for your meal is the same as stealing," said the police officer.
"The restaurant wants justice.
So next week you have to go to court and let a jury decide your punishment."
When he went to court, the judge asked,
"Do you have anything to say, Matthew?"
He said, "I am full of sorrow for what I've done.
Now I know that real friends won't ask you to do something illegal."
The jury then let him have his liberty. But they made Matthew pick up garbage as a punishment.
Much to Matthew's surprise, he ended up meeting some new friends.