The Circus
Ben was unhappy.
He lived on a ranch near a small town,
and he didn't have many friends.
Then one day, a messenger came to the ranch.
He showed the headline in the town newspaper.
The circus was coming to the town.
It even coincided with Ben's birthday!
Ben was very excited as his father steered the car through the town.
The circus couldn't accommodate all the people who wanted to see the show, but Ben had a ticket.
Ben peered at the activity around him.
He watched people of both genders dance all around.
They wore funny costumes, and their hair was dyed many different colors.
Also, tame tigers with stripes on their fur did tricks.
Outside, people could commission an informal portrait.
They posed in front of a funny picture while an artist quickly drew them.
Ben couldn't believe it.
He was happier than he had ever been before.
That day, Ben knew what he wanted to do.
He loved the circus to such an extent that he wanted to have his own circus when he grew older.
Seeing the circus was like a dose of medicine for him.
He wasn't unhappy anymore.
He felt special.
He inquired about what he needed to do to have his own circus.
He studied hard and learned about business.
Ben worked very hard, and one day, he had his own circus.
It was a great circus.
People told him that he could be very rich.
But he wasn't tempted by money.
He just wanted to make children happy.
He knew the circus had changed his life,
and he wanted to do the same thing for others.