An Interesting Life
A man looked through some boxes with his grandson.
They were filled with old photographs and objects that portrayed important events from the grandfather's life.
He wished to share the circumstances behind each event with his grandson.
The grandson, however, thought his grandfather's stories were boring.
The grandfather coped with this.
He ignored his grandson's criticism.
He took a photo from the box.
"That's the submarine I was on during the war," he explained.
The grandson gazed at it.
The grandfather glanced at the next picture and frowned.
It showed a row of coffins.
His grandson noticed the grief in his grandfather's face.
"What is it?" the boy inquired.
"This was after a nuclear bomb was dropped," the grandfather answered.
"It devastated a city."
Next, the grandfather pulled a toy microscope from the box and rotated it in his hand.
"Where did you get that?" the grandson asked.
"This is a souvenir I bought at the science museum," the grandfather said.
Now, the boy was really interested.
He started to understand that his grandfather was telling him a larger story.
It was the story of his grandfather's life.
The grandfather picked up another photo.
It showed a young bride and groom.
They were very happy.
A certificate was attached to the photo.
The boy couldn't read it, but he traced his finger over the paper.
"What's this from, Granddad?" he asked.
"That's my marriage license from the day I married your grandmother," the grandfather said.
"Wow!" said the boy.
"Granddad, now I know all about your life!"