Everyone Is Special
When I was young, everything that went wrong in my house seemed to be my fault.
Once, my brothers tried to make cookies.
They blended flour and ginger and made a disgusting paste.
Then, they tried to wash it down the drain,
but it got all over the floor.
Later, my brothers said that I had done it, and I had to wipe it up.
I worried that my parents liked them more than me.
One autumn day, I was sure I would make my parents proud.
I bought a model rocket.
After I put it together,
I invited everybody to watch it.
I wanted my brothers to envy my technical knowledge.
I lit the fuse, but nothing happened.
"Looks like your fireworks don't work.
I hope you kept the receipt so you can return them," my brother said.
"It's not a firework!" I screamed.
They were making fun of me again.
I didn't know what went wrong.
I hadn't altered anything.
I quickly moved the wires on the bottom, hoping that would help.
Suddenly, the rocket flew up.
We stood aside as it curved through the grass and ran straight into the mailbox.
Then, the mailbox collapsed.
The rocket was crushed.
Embarrassed, I ran inside and hid.
A few minutes later, my mom asked, "Are you OK?"
"I just wanted them to be jealous of me for once.
Now, I see why you and Dad don't love me as much as you love them," I said.
"That's not true!" said my mom.
"See my fingers... Each one is different.
You kids are like my fingers: all are different,
but I love them all the same."
I embraced her.
Now, I know that my parents love me just as much as my brothers.