How Did Greenland Get Its Name?
The nation of Greenland isn't very green.
The sun's rays don't shine there for three whole months.
As a result, it's covered with snow, ice, and frost.
Then, how was the name derived?
It started with a Viking named Erik the Red.
Erik had many merits.
However, there was an underlying problem: he got angry easily.
People were scared of him.
However, he was married to the niece of a very powerful man.
So, everybody tried to be nice to him.
One day, Erik fought with his neighbor and killed him.
His consequent punishment was to leave Iceland.
Many stories circulated about a land west of Iceland.
But only a fraction of the people in Iceland believed them.
Still, Erik wanted to find it.
Erik sailed toward the land via the Atlantic Ocean.
His marine knowledge was good, but the trip was hard.
Some of his men drowned.
Erik's lieutenant wanted to resign from his position.
Others thought about committing suicide.
Suddenly, Erik thought he saw something.
"I don't believe it," said Erik.
"It must be an illusion."
But it was no trick - it was the new land!
Erik trembled in the cold polar air.
He saw that there was ice everywhere.
He realized that the ice could keep enemies out.
Not even the best navy could invade the new land.
He could start a new dynasty in his name.
But how could he convince people to live here?
"I'll call it Greenland," he said.
Erik's plan worked.
Within two years, over a thousand people moved to Greenland.