The Boy Who Saved the Town
Marcus lived in a small suburb near the sea.
He was a stubborn boy, and he only cared about himself.
His father worked as a chemist for a large institution and wanted Marcus to get a job there.
Instead, the boy delivered milk.
Every morning, he took dairy products to the grocers.
One day, Marcus was jogging down the street that descended into the lower part of the town with a gallon of milk to give to a merchant.
He didn't want to be late.
He ran down a path beside a large canal.
A wall there kept water from coming into the town during high tide.
But Marcus saw a small hole in the wall.
Marcus knew that if the wall broke,
it would be a tragedy for the town.
At first, he hesitated.
He had to choose between helping himself and helping the town.
There was only one way to save the town.
It seemed crazy to him, but it was the only thing he could do.
He poked his finger into the hole.
This didn't fix the problem forever, but it did postpone the tragedy.
His finger ached.
He felt the chill of the arctic water as it splashed him.
There was no one else around.
He knew he had to wait until the tide went out again.
It was very difficult, but Marcus stayed there and saved the town.
Once the tide had gone out, Marcus told everyone what happened.
A group of people went to the wall.
They saw the hole and fixed it.
Everyone was very happy with Marcus.
The local congress even gave him a gift for saving the town.
He was a hero.