Climbing Kilimanjaro
With great ambition, it is now possible for everyone in good health to attempt climbing Mt. Kilimanjaro (5,895m).
The path to the top of Africa's tallest mountain has many cabins for climbers to use, while other routes have caves where people can camp.
Unlike other mighty mountains such as Everest and K2 in the Himalayas, Kilimanjaro can be climbed even by novices.
For this reason, a growing contingent of people who are fond of adventure are coming to Tanzania.
Still, not every optimist's dreams will come true, and several will be forced to turn back mid-hike.
What impairs some climbers and makes others successful? Kilimanjaro is only for people who are sufficiently prepared.
If you become ill, there is no ambulance to take you to the hospital.
Instead, your guides will have to haul you down the mountain if you break your ankle or have difficulty breathing the thin mountain air.
For this reason, burning calories by exercising before the trip is vital.
Healthy nutrition is also strongly recommended in order to ensure you have ample energy and are as strong as possible.
Some people exert themselves too much by attempting to rush to the top, acting as if they were trying to meet a deadline.
These impatient climbers often turn back due to exhaustion and sickness.
Instead, those who flank the group and proceed slowly are more likely to get to the top.
Guides make efforts to forbid people from climbing too quickly, constantly whispering "pole, pole," which means "slowly, slowly" in Kiswahili.
Those who successfully haul themselves to the top have a great reward.
The views are breathtaking. Sadly, because of global warming, much of the ice on the mountaintop has melted in recent years.
Before long, there will be none left at all.
For this reason, many people are marking their calendars and planning trips to Tanzania, hoping to see the beauty of the icy summit before it's too late.