Laika, the Space Dog
One of the world's most beloved space travelers was also the furriest.
Laika was a little dog living on the streets of Moscow, Russia.
She matured on the streets because no one would give her a home.
She had to learn how to live without eating much. She found ways to keep warm in a very cold climate.
Scientists thought a tough dog like Laika would do well in a project they were putting together.
In a prior launch, Russia had put the first man-made object into space.
Now, scientists wanted to see if a living thing could go into space.
Although many facts about space had been learned, they weren't enough to help send humans into space safely yet.
Laika and two other dogs were chosen to help scientists with their research.
The animals were used in a variety of tests. In the end, though, only Laika would go into space.
On November 3, 1957 the Sputnik 2 spaceship was due to leave Earth.
Scientists carefully applied wires to Laika's skin to measure her body's reactions once she got into space.
Laika also wore a special leash. Without it,she would float around in the spaceship.
Soon after, Laika left the planet. Scientists on Earth awaited information from the ship.
But in the midst of so much excitement, something very sad happened.
Scientists were able to tell that Laika was under a lot of stress.
The trip confused and scared her. Laika's entire ship had become as hot as a furnace.
Scientists were powerless to help the dog in her misery. After about five hours, Laika died.
Some have complained that the little dog should never have been used in the mission.
Scientists knew that she would not survive the trip.
Laika was never buried, but a memorial has been established in Moscow.
There are many songs and books about her, too. It seems that Laika became a hero to many people.