The Magic Computer
I had a difficult geography project to finish by the end of the semester.
My teacher wanted it to be typewritten, so I went to the school computer room.
But when I got there, all the computers were turned off.
Apparently, there was a recent problem, and technicians were fixing it.
I knew of some private study rooms downstairs.
They were small and dark, and the computers were very old, but I had no choice.
At least the computers were operating correctly.
I typed and highlighted the assignment's title: "Evaluate the Government's Response to Global Warming."
But I didn't know what to write in my essay.
Finally, I decided to find a book to help me.
I went to the library, checked the book indexes, and eventually found a useful book.
Then, I returned to the computer.
When I looked at the screen, I saw something so weird that I nearly fainted!
The essay was complete! Had somebody in cyberspace written it?
I didn't know, but I was very happy. I printed it out and handed it in. I got an "A."
After that, I used the computer for all my assignments.
I'd type the title, wait awhile, and the computer would do it.
Every assignment was perfect; I never had to edit anything.
I stopped paying attention to my teacher's lectures and spent my extra time in the gymnasium.
And my grades got better and better.
A month later, I was walking into class when my friend said, "Are you prepared for the test?"
"What test?" I asked. "The geography test!" he replied."
I hope you studied. It's worth 70 percent of our final grade!"
I failed the test, of course, I was completely ignorant about the subject.
After that, I made a resolution never to use the magic computer again.
The moral of this story is that if you cheat at school, you won't learn anything.