Growing to be Great
When George was just a boy, he didn't have any parents.
The rumor was that they had died in a car accident.
Many bad things could have happened to George, but he was lucky.
He was sent to live alongside other children without parents.
There were kind people to assist George and help him go forward with his life.
However, he was a pessimistic and mean little boy.
George was often outraged. He told mean rumors about the other kids.
He smashed furniture and even slapped other boys.
He defied anyone who tried to help him, and soon it was difficult for them to forgive him.
But George did display a love for one thing. He loved to play baseball.
Whereas he was lazy in school and liked neither the subjects nor the teachers, he was lively and happy when he played baseball.
One of George's teachers noticed his talent.
He began to work with the boy. At first, they only talked about baseball.
The teacher watched George play. He was a very efficient hitter.
He almost never missed the ball. The teacher thought that George looked majestic when he played.
When George hit the ball, it flew through the breeze as if it would never come down.
In time, they began to talk about other things.
They talked about George's family and his dreams for the future.
They developed a very good relationship.
As George got older, he began to grow.
His appetite was huge. He ate and ate. He got stronger.
Soon the other boys and even the teachers looked small and feeble next to him.
Everyone thought that this was the start of a great baseball career.
When George got his first job as a baseball player, he gave most of his wages to the people who had helped him as a boy.
He hoped that other children would also find a way to live happy successful lives.