The Heirs
Martin, Paul, and Tom were brothers. They were very different, but they were consistent about two things.
They couldn't succeed in business, and they never agreed about anything.
Martin was a hardworking farmer, growing organic vegetables and raising poultry.
But he was disorganized and forgot to pay his bills. Paul owned a textile factory that produced clothes.
He was organized, but he was greedy and used too much for his own clothing.
His wardrobe was filled with his own products. Tom was once a sergeant in the army.
He ran a martial arts school, but his stance on discipline was too strong. He had almost no students.
One day, they received a telegraph saying that their father had died. They were heirs to his old farm.
They planned to sell it as soon as possible, so they went to see it even though there was a terrible storm.
The house didn't look great, but there was a lot of land. There was so much, in fact, that they could barely see its boundary.
Suddenly, the storm got worse. The sheer force of the wind almost knocked them over.
Martin said, "Look, it's a typhoon!" Paul said, "No, it's a cyclone." Tom said, "No, it's a tornado!"
They argued until Paul began to wail and said, "Whatever it is, it's coming right at us! We're doomed!"
The three brothers scrambled inside the old house.
Martin said, "If we survive, we must stop fighting. This farm could be great if we fixed it up.
With my hard work, Paul's organization, and Tom's discipline, we could run a great business together!"
The storm finally ended. And luckily, it didn't wreck the farm.
"Just think," Martin said, "it took the chaos of a typhoon to bring us together."
Paul replied, "You mean a cyclone brought us together." Tom said, "Didn't I tell you both that it was a tornado?"
The brothers never agreed on what kind of storm it was, but by combining their skills, they started a successful farm.