The Singing Emperor
Nero was emperor of Rome from 54 CE to 68 CE, when a coup put an end to his young life.
For some, he was a powerful ruler of incredible glamour, yet the consensus among most Romans was that he was a terrible emperor;
some even called him a beast and used the numbers 666 as a code for his name.
Even today, this number is a symbol of the devil for many people.
The chapels near the graves of the people Nero killed are some of the most famous churches in the world,
but there was never a cry of outrage over the grave of Nero.
Why did commentators think that Nero was so bad?
He was a cynical man who harassed every member of his family, killing his stepfather, stepbrother, stepsister, wife, and even his own mother.
He first tried to drown her in the sea, but she swam to safety, so he sent an assassin to finish the job.
He tried to con the Roman people into believing that he was sorry, yet no one did.
Soon afterward, most of Rome burned in a fire.
The tragedy inflamed the people, and many thought that Nero was the one who had started the blaze.
Some say he even sang the melodies of well-known songs while the capital burned.
Nero blamed Christians for the fire and tortured them to death.
After the fire, Nero built a beautiful palace with a giant dome over it, calling it his Golden House.
A giant statue sporting Nero's hairdo and beard stood over the palace, which also had a large swimming pool and a garden that was illuminated by burning lamps.
Nero built a long bridge to join the palace to the forum, Rome's central market.
He would sing songs on the rooftop and entertain anyone who listened.
Many enjoyed his glamorous style, but others hated him for his selfishness.
Nero's reign came to an abrupt end when the army organized a conspiracy against him.
The soldiers wanted a new emperor, and everyone left Nero to die.
While stabbing himself in the neck, he exclaimed in agony, "What a great artist the world is losing!"
Soon after, a war began. When it was over, the new emperor tore down the hated Golden House of Nero forever.