Janie and the Music Player
Janie had constant thoughts about getting a music player.
One day, she was late to class.
She hurried down the hall but halted when she saw a backpack on the floor.
She looked inside and found nothing but some books.
She reached inside the bag and felt a small object at the bottom.
It was a music player enclosed in a black case!
Janie tended to be honest, and she had no valid reason to take the device.
However, her desire for the player influenced her decision.
She slyly put the device into her own backpack.
When she arrived at class, she gave her teacher the bag. "I found this," she said.
Ms. Johnson asked, "Does this backpack belong to anyone?"
A girl named Linda claimed the bag.
Linda looked inside and yelled, "My music player is missing! Janie took it!"
Janie answered, "I did not."
Linda responded, "You were the only one that had access to it!
If your version of the story is true, you'll let Ms. Johnson check your bag."
Janie started to perspire as she realized the impending trouble she was in.
She gripped her bag tightly. Ms. Johnson took the bag from Janie. Inside she found the player.
"Janie, I never expected this kind of conduct from you," she said.
"You've always been such a good student." Ms. Johnson gave Linda the player.
Linda said, "Ms. Johnson, look!" There was a crack along one side.
She turned it to the "on" mode, but it wouldn't work.
It must've snapped while Janie was holding onto the bag so tightly.
Ms. Johnson called Janie's parents. They were very upset.
"Stealing is illegal. You have no respect for the law whatsoever," they said.
"We bought you a music player, but we're giving it to Linda. It will replace the one you broke."
In the end, Janie's bad behavior left her with nothing at all.