The Fossil Hunters
Tim and Dean were great fossil hunters. They were the very best at finding dinosaur bones.
Although Tim and Dean were quite similar, they were outright enemies.
The two men got into vicious arguments all the time.
They couldn't coexist peacefully because their egos were too large.
Tim thought he was the best fossil hunter, while Dean was sure that he was much better than Tim.
One day, Tim was searching for fossils on the periphery of the city when he stumbled on a huge thigh bone.
He had never seen anything like it! He took his shovel and carefully excavated the dirt around it.
As he dug, he uncovered more jagged bones. He realized that he had found an entire dinosaur skeleton!
Tim couldn't conceive of the magnitude of the find.
He could not think of a plan to remove the huge skeleton all by himself.
Such an endeavor would be beyond his capability. He needed help.
He tried to think of people who would be capable of helping him remove the skeleton without breaking it.
The only person Tim could think of was Dean, his enemy. Tim ran into the city to find Dean.
Tim found him and said, "Dean, I've found the skeletal remains of a huge animal.
But I can't get the skeleton out by myself. Will you please help me?"
Dean thought that Tim's claim might be dubious. He replied, "If you're serious about the skeleton, I'll help."
Tim excitedly showed Dean the skeleton's locale. They worked together to carefully remove each bone.
To keep the bones together, they tied them with elastic strips.
When they were finished, they had uncovered a perfect skeleton.
They used plaster to make a mold of the dinosaur's skull.
They engraved their initials into it and gave it to the curator of a local museum.
Tim and Dean found out that they could work very well together.
They decided to end their feud and become friends.
By combining their talents, the men became even greater than they were before.