Life on the Farm
Bill was an excellent capitalist. He financed a large aviation enterprise that made a lot of money.
He knew how to maximize monetary gains in every business deal he made.
Bill had one big problem, though. He was unhappy all the time.
Bill knew that he had to do something about it or he would be depressed for the rest of his life.
One day, Bill was in his office when he heard a knock at the door.
"Come in!" Bill said loudly. His accountant, Jane, walked in.
Jane said, "Sir, I haven't seen you smile in a year. What are you so sad about? Your company is doing very well."
Bill told her, "I'm indifferent about my company's success. I have contempt toward my job. I just want to do something I enjoy.
I've always loved growing plants as a hobby. I'm going to quit my job and become a farmer!"
"You're crazy!" Jane said.  "I don't think so," Bill replied.
"I want the simplicity of a life on a farm. I'm tired of all this stress. Farming will make me happy."
The very next day, Bill carried out the preliminary task of buying land and tools.
Then he got to work. He sowed many types of seeds. He planted tomatoes, cabbage, carrots, and onions.
"The upcoming summer is going to be very dry," thought Bill.
"I need to irrigate my crops as a precaution in case it doesn't rain enough."
He took his spade and dug a ditch down the middle of his farm.
"Water from the stream will flow down the ditch and saturate the soil around every plant," Bill thought.
Bill dedicated himself to farming. After a year, his farm was producing very good crops.
Most importantly, Bill was happy. He finally had the life he always wanted.