The Man and the Monkey
While flying over a jungle, a wealthy executive's private plane crashed.
Some of the crew were hurt, so the pilot decided to stay with them and wait for help.
The arrogant executive, though, didn't care about the welfare of the pilot and crew.
Rather, he thought he could walk out of the jungle and find a town to stay in.
He followed a trail through a canyon and along a creek. The jungle was actually very stunning.
If the arrogant executive had stopped to look around, he might have perceived the jungle's beauty.
But he was in a nasty mood and had no care for the aesthetic value of the jungle.
He continued to walk up the steep incline of the jungle's hills.
Soon, he was lost. Several days passed, and fatigue and hunger weakened him.
He was very tired and afraid. Just then, a monkey came out of the trees.
It was carrying a twig covered in honey. It walked up to a mound where termites lived.
He then used the twig like a drill to make a hole in the mound.
Then very carefully, it removed the twig from the hole. The sticky twig was covered with termites.
Instead of eating the bugs, the monkey offered them to the executive, but he didn't want what the monkey offered.
He shouted at the monkey, "Get away from me, you stupid primate!"
The executive's stereotype of the monkey was wrong. The monkey was not stupid.
It knew how to find food, whereas the executive did not. He refused the help of the monkey, thereby leaving himself to starve.
When the executive was finally found, he was very skinny and sick. He had not eaten for a very long time.
Because he held a bias against the primitive ways of the monkey, he had gone hungry and almost died.
The executive didn't understand that it was his arrogant attitude that had caused all of his problems.