The Nurse's Lesson
One of the children in the nursery was sick.
The child's mother, who usually chattered constantly, was quiet and worried.
She knew that if she did not act quickly, the child's condition would deteriorate.
She summoned the children's nurse and said to her,
"The monks make a medicine that can cure my child's sickness. Please, hurry tonight to the monastery and get it."
The nurse immediately hurried from the manor to get the medicine.
The monastery was far away, and she had to walk along a dark and winding trail.
The temperature was close to zero degrees centigrade, and it was raining.
Luckily, the nurse had grabbed her raincoat beforehand.
She zipped it up and pulled the hood over her head. "I'll never make it there," she thought.
"Perhaps I should return and go in the morning." But she remembered the sick child and decided to continue.
She could see the gleam of a light in the distance, and finally, she arrived at the monastery.
It was very late. She feared the monks would not be hospitable.
But she approached the door and knocked anyway. The rain had condensed on the exterior of the windows by the door.
All she could see was the blurred profile of a large man coming to answer the door.
Again, she was filled with fear. But the monk smiled at her with good humor when he opened the door.
He took her outstretched hand and welcomed her with a hearty voice.
The place was warm, and she heard a concerto playing in another room. She relaxed.
"How can I help you?" the monk asked, and the nurse explained the situation.
He instantly knew what to do. He grabbed a parcel of medicine and took her back to the manor in a carriage.
The medicine worked. The nurse was happy she had kept going through the bad weather and found the monastery.
Now the boy would be able to get better, and the mother would be happy again.