Jen's New Job
The history museum needed to recruit a new tour guide.
The director interviewed dozens of applicants before he decided to hire Jen.
She was chosen because she was friendly, punctual, and had a great attitude.
On her first day, Jen got to work and prepared to give her first tour.
She looked at the names on the register.
She saw that the Queen of England and a diplomat were visiting the museum.
She thought, "It's my very first day, and I have to impress a monarch!
I hope I don't humiliate myself in front of a person of such renown!"
Jen was nervous. She took a deep breath and said, "Hello, everyone! I'm going to talk to you about the chronology of ancient Egypt."
As she turned around to show the group some artifacts, she bumped into a copy of a fossil of an authentic elephant tusk.
It fell to the ground and broke into a million pieces!
"Oh no!" said Jen to herself. "I sure hope the rest of the tour goes better than this!"
The rest of the tour did not go any better. She tripped over an antique vase and broke a piece off of it.
As she was reading an excerpt from a lyric poem, she sneezed and tore a page of the epic.
After the tour, Jen approached the queen to apologize.
She said, "I'm sorry, Your Majesty. I was a terrible tour guide. Let me give you a refund for the money you spent."
The Queen laughed and said, "I didn't pay so there is no need for a refund, Jen. I loved the tour.
You just have to be a little more careful and work hard to become the best at your job. Hard work precedes success."
Jen smiled and thanked the Queen. She decided to be extra careful from then on.
She was persistent and worked hard. In time, Jen became the best tour guide at the museum.