Dangerous Bites
There are many animals with dangerous bites in the world, but which one is the worst?
People assume snakes are the most dangerous.
Some would say that the elusive short-tailed mamushi has the worst bite.
The snake only goes into homes in pursuit of pests such as mice.
Otherwise, it stays in the fields, where it's dangerous to people who search for food there.
Usually, it is reluctant to attack humans, but if someone stuns it by accidentally stepping on it, it bites to protect itself.
At first, the effects of the bite may seem minor and negligible because it doesn't cause a lot of bleeding.
However, after a few moments, the venom induces paralysis in the area where the individual was bitten.
Furthermore, the venom can also interfere with breathing.
If the person doesn't go to the doctor, they are susceptible to kidney deterioration.
Others would argue that tigers have the worst bite.
Mother tigers are inseparable from their babies and seem to be the gentlest creatures when they are around their young.
However, if the babies are threatened, the mother tiger's savage nature prevails to ensure their safety.
With strong jaws and the ability to move quickly, the tiger can kill someone with one bite.
That's because it always tries to bite an important artery when it attacks.
If the artery is ruptured, the victim will bleed to death.
In the mainstream, animal bites are seen as the most dangerous.
But some scientists think this idea is invalid.
In fact, the most dangerous bite might be the human bite.
When scientists magnified the contents in human Saliva, they found about three hundred different microbes in it.
A human bite can be dangerous if the bacteria enters the body through a cut, which can make people very sick.
Furthermore, most people don't realize how serious a human bite can be, so they don't go to the doctor right away.
This gives the wound a chance to get infected and cause more problems.