Social Media
All around the world, people who have mobile devices are likely to have a presence on social media.
However, data reveals a link between social media use and a surge in health issues.
Anxiety and depression are two such issues.
Research suggests that social media use may be correlated to lower self-control.
Lower self-control often causes poor or addictive behavior.
Social media has been described to be more addictive than tobacco and alcohol.
People may rely on social media as a form of escapism and for mood-modifying effects.
These are similar to the reasons people become dependent on addictive substances.
Surveys about social media show that a surprising number of teenagers have been subjected to cyberbullying.
Cyberbullies can easily remain anonymous.
They are accountable to no one, so they use social media to target victims and spread rumors.
This has become so common that the term "keyboard warrior" has been coined.
A keyboard warrior's agenda is to write abusive posts while staying hidden.
The effects of cyberbullying can be traumatic.
There are other negative effects of social media's popularity.
People sometimes use social networking platforms to show their best selves.
A recent social media trend is to upload and broadcast video clips to share a piece of one's life.
However, instead of feeling accepted and validated, people end up comparing their lives with other people.
This trap of comparing lives may lead to symptoms of depression.
Social media use has also been linked to feelings of social isolation.
The more people use social media,
the more they realize that their digital friends may not actually be real friends.
This feeling of isolation may cause a person to experience extreme loneliness.
We see social media used in the personal and professional lives of those around us.
It's apparent that it's here to stay.
Therefore, it's necessary to consider the importance of educating people on how to use social media effectively and safely.