Women in Tech
The digital economy is soaring.
There are over seven million jobs in the computer science and technology industries in the United States alone.
Yet there is still a major gender gap when it comes to women in tech.
These women face many challenges, as seen in a quit rate of 41 percent.
So what can be done to close this gender gap?
How can we ensure fair pay and equal opportunities?
First, women need to be inspired and motivated to enter the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), as well as computer science.
According to statistics, 74 percent of young women express interest in STEM subjects and computer science.
However, women hold only 18 percent of undergraduate computer science degrees and 26 percent of tech jobs.
Early education must convey technology as a tool that can be applied to real life to solve problems.
Many young women are put off because they view the technology sector to be too male-dominated.
Women lack prominent roles, holding only a mere five percent of tech leadership positions.
Therefore, women who are already in tech positions must act as mentors and endorse other women in these fields.
They can play a huge role for young women by giving them encouragement, support, and guidance.
These women can help attract and retain more women and, therefore, create a level-playing field.
However, it is not just the women in tech who must be vocal.
Men working in the tech industry have a responsibility to listen to women and foster a comfortable work culture.
The leaders in the industry have the power to create new opportunities and promote the inclusion of women to close this gender gap.
There must be a systematic approach from schools to workplaces, including the motivation of young women to study STEM and computer science.
Women must provide support and mentorship, and men must listen to and encourage women.
If we continue to empower women in the tech sector, it will be good for everyone.