The Ketogenic Diet
Many diets come and go.
One diet that has gained a significant following is the ketogenic diet.
This diet is a low-carbohydrate, moderate-protein, high-fat diet.
Many swear by it, claiming that it has improved their overall health.
Known health benefits are weight loss, diabetes management, increased mental focus and energy, and epilepsy control.
An average person's main energy source is glucose.
When food that is high in carbohydrates is consumed, the body produces glucose.
Since glucose is used for energy, fats are not needed and are, therefore, stored.
By lowering the intake of carbohydrates and increasing fat intake, the body goes into a metabolic state known as ketosis.
This is when the liver breaks down fats and produces ketones, which then become the main energy source.
The body then becomes extremely efficient at burning fat for energy.
Therefore, the goal of a ketogenic diet is to keep your body in this state.
In a ketogenic diet, carbs are strictly limited and should come from vegetables, nuts, and dairy.
Refined carbs, such as wheat, starch, and fruit, are not allowed.
This means pasta, bread, potatoes, and beans as well as all fruit are to be avoided.
The majority of meals should include meat, fatty fish, eggs, leafy greens, dairy, and healthy oils such as olive oil, coconut oil, and avocado.
A ketogenic diet has a lot of positive benefit; however, there are side effects.
Some include cramping, constipation, heart palpitations, and reduced physical performance.
As a precaution, you should always check with your doctor before you start any form of dieting.
In summary, eating more fat, a moderate amount of protein, and few carbohydrates will put your body into ketosis.
Your body will use up the fat as energy.
This diet can be a powerful tool for good health and weight loss.