The Bachelor's Lesson
A keen young bachelor had finished his studies at the university.
He had completed his studies in the minimum time and was about to start looking for a job.
As soon as he had received his diploma, he thought that he was the smartest person in town.
"I excel at everything I study," he said, bragging about his knowledge.
"I've mastered psychology.
I even understand the great theoretical teachings of science, such as relativity.
There is nothing that I don't know.
Whether it's the movements of celestial objects, like planets and stars, or how to use the power of radioactive substances, I know everything.
But actually, there was something the bachelor did not know.
Although his analytic abilities were great, he failed to notice he was missing something very important in his life.
One day while walking through town, the bachelor witnessed a collision between two cars.
Both drivers appeared to be injured, but the scholar only stood and watched.
He thought to himself, "Those idiots should have been more alert. They really must not be very competent."
He never thought the drivers needed help.
"Please help me," said the female driver in a weak voice.
"Help me, too," said the male driver. "I'm hurt and can't move."
Suddenly, the bachelor realized he was the only person in the area near the accident.
He quit thinking and ran to help the drivers using his medical knowledge.
He carefully helped them out of their vehicles and then called an ambulance.
The drivers were saved, and furthermore the bachelor felt the best he had in his entire life.
Studying sociology and geology didn't give him this wonderful feeling.
It was the act of helping others, not his cognitive skills, that gave him this great feeling.
He had learned an important lesson.
He learned that intellect isn't everything; being helpful is just as important.
"Having only a brain is not enough," he thought.
"An integral part of being alive is also having a heart."