Preparing for Future
Overpopulation is a big problem in every region of the world today.
Too many people are crammed into cities and towns around the globe.
Earth's population is about 6.5 billion people.
This number is growing every day.
Notwithstanding improvements in birth control, in just 50 years, the population will be almost 9 billion.
Many people worry that the Earth won't have enough resources to support so many people.
One major reason for this is that wasting resources and polluting have become habitual behaviors.
Industrial output results in polluting the air with dangerous fumes.
Also, cars and machines waste important natural resources like oil and water.
It's possible that the Earth may become so damaged that it cannot support a large population of humans.
Another issue is the lack of useful land for cultivating crops.
Even today, many people subsist on mere scraps of food and little water.
In 50 years, many experts worry that huge numbers of people will starve to death.
So, what is being done to prepare for the future?
People are realizing they can no longer justify their wasteful behavior or defer action to fix it.
Many car companies already have patents for very efficient cars.
Such cars waste no resources and produce no pollution.
A conversion to clean cars means that petroleum can be saved for the future.
In addition, the environmental sectors of many governments are setting strict rules for industries that pollute too much.
If companies do not keep to these standards, they are penalized with higher taxes.
In some cases, their operations might be suspended altogether.
Food is also an issue that is being tackled.
Many countries are now subscribing to the point of view that immediate action is needed.
They are determining ways to export goods to people in need, so that no one goes hungry.
Experts will continue to come up with ideas for the future, and a synthesis of these ideas will help to support the growing population.