Impressionism
Impressionism is a movement that began in France in the late 19th century.
It is considered to be the first modern art movement, as it was seen as a departure from other art.
This is because it violated the established rules of academic painting.
Unlike realistic academic paintings, impressionist paintings are characterized by the depiction of light on objects.
The artists aim to capture the light rather than the details in order to show an impression of time.
This distinctive quality is achieved by using two key techniques.
The first is a technique called "impasto."
Impasto is an Italian word that means "mixture."
In painting, impasto describes short, thick strokes.
This technique allows the artist to control the reflection and movement of light on the canvas.
The artist can modify the width and direction of the paint strokes to convey texture and give the painting a three-dimensional quality.
Also, the speed and strength of the strokes can convey the artist's perception of the subject.
The second technique is optical mixing.
This involves the use of broken colors.
In other words, instead of the traditional practice of mixing an array of colors on a palette, artists paint different colors side by side.
Doing this adds texture and plays on light.
And it creates the illusion of different colors.
Another difference between impressionist paintings and traditional paintings is the subject matter.
During that time period, the accepted subjects were historical or literary-themes.
They were often based on religious or mythological subjects.
Impressionists, on the other hand, preferred landscapes and contemporary life.
They often painted outdoors, using the sunlight to depict a brighter style.
Even though photography was starting to become popular, impressionists avoided representing reality.
They demonstrated their individualism by playing with color and blurring the lines between the subject and the background.
In the mid-19th century, the middle class in Paris saw rapid growth.
The city saw an increase in cafés, cinemas, parks, and boutiques.
Impressionists captured the daily lives of the middle class, which appealed to the wider public,
and eventually led to the acceptance of impressionism into the art world.