The New Bioco
Jack got a new job at a biotechnology company called Bioco.
Bioco manufactured drugs to treat diabetes and high cholesterol.
Jack's job was to use a tiny mechanism to get nectar from flowers.
The nectar was a main ingredient in the drugs.
Jack liked his job, and he thought that Bioco was a caring company.
However, Jack soon learned that the company wasn't as kind as he first thought.
Bioco's motto was "Make the Earth a Better Place."
However, this motto was deceptive.
The company actually did a number of really bad things to the environment.
The company produced a lot of smog and harmful acid.
Bioco poured the acid in a nearby river, which killed the fish.
The waste from the factory also caused erosion of the river banks.
After a few weeks at the new job, Jack saw all the bad things Bioco was doing.
He had always had strong ethics, and he knew he had to do something.
One day, while the Bioco workers were eating in the cafeteria, Jack stood up and gave a speech.
He said, "My fellow coworkers, I know you have all seen the evil things our company is doing.
I have a notion that we can fix them if we form a coalition.
We can go to the administration and tell them we'll quit if they don't eliminate the problems.
They'll have no choice but to listen to us."
Jack explained what they were to do.
His coworkers liked his explicit plan.
They went to the administrative offices and demanded that Bioco stop damaging the environment, or they all would quit.
One supervisor said to them, "Thank you for being straightforward about this issue.
Since I can't afford to lose all of you workers, I guess we'll just have to fix things."
Jack, his supervisor, and his coworkers spent the next month designing a new framework for the company.
They cleaned up the acid from the river and minimized the amount of air pollution the company released.
At last, under this new regime, the company's motto was more suitable.